Take a good look, Zeke.
That's Liberio, where we live.
Compared to the world,
it's like a tiny birdcage.
Since we can't leave,
we have to live here till we die.
Zeke, wouldn't you like to leave?
Yeah, I would.
Oh, what's this? We hardly ever
get visitors this early.
I'll come back later.
It's okay. We're on our way out.
Oh, Eldians?
Wh-What?! We got permission
to leave the walls!
It's my job to clean the tower
and get rid of trash.
You came in here and defiled it, you devils!
Your kind slaughtered countless lives!
Yet here you are, pumping out kids?!
Devils!
Stay in the internment zone!
You guys stink!
--Thanks for ruining my day!
--Remember this well, Zeke.
This is the outside world.
If you don't like it, you've gotta change it.
Zeke, you're going to save everyone.
"Sole Salvation"
One of these kids will be my successor?
Yes, we'll choose one.
One of them is falling behind. Who's that?
Ah. Jaeger again?
All the other kids are fiercely competing
to be Honorary Marleyans.
Yet he has none of that drive.
Why does he even come here?
How was training, Zeke?
It's really tough.
I see. But I know you can be a Warrior.
Because you have a special power.
And most important of all, you're our son!
Right!
Father, Mother. Thanks for watching Zeke.
Yeah.
I baked your favorite pie today.
Yippee!
Your social dance club again? Zeke misses you.
But it's for the wellness of Liberio.
Someday, I'm sure Zeke will
understand why we're doing this.
This is the Tragedy of Lago
that occurred 1,200 years ago.
After Lago was destroyed in a single day,
the Titans went on to cause the Horrors
of Valle and Ravaging of Monte.
Marleyans in the tens of thousands
were killed by Eldia.
What's more, the people who escaped
Lago fled into the countryside.
However, the Eldian Empire
put Titans along the path,
and at daybreak, the Titans
rose and attacked the--
Yeah, I know. A lot of people died.
Is your father teaching you our actual history?
He says Eldians did horrible things
to Marleyans, so we have to atone for it.
Do you want to become a Warrior
and fight for Marley?
Yeah. I want to be a Warrior.
Well, I think it's bedtime.
Oh! Next time you're here,
I'll read you the cat house book!
Yay!
Begin!
You're awful at this, Dad!
Dad!
Zeke?
I finished early today! Let's--
Oh, good. We'll be able to study more.
Right...
In other words, the Tragedy
of Lago never happened.
The Ravaging of Monte and Horrors of Valle
are stories made up by Marley, too.
Eldians have never had such cruel
customs or culture. After all--
The Founder Ymir wouldn't
want that. It's unthinkable.
That's right! You're catching on, Zeke!
Yeah!
If you're not serious, get lost!
Marley needs people willing to
give everything to our motherland.
We sure as hell won't leave a Titan
in the hands of someone like you.
Hey! You there! Can you toss that ball back?
You've got a good arm for a kid!
Huh?
Here!
Nice catch!
I'm sick of throwing off the wall.
You mind playing for a bit?
A red armband! You're--!
One of the Marleyan Warriors
you're aiming to be.
Though, since my Beast Titan
isn't too helpful in war,
I mostly just play catch around here.
The name's Tom Ksaver.
I work in Titan research.
So, what's your name?
Zeke Jaeger!
Zeke, your throw has some heat!
You'd be a good pitcher.
I'm home! Dad, guess what?
That's not what you told me!
What gives, Grice? If Zeke isn't
chosen, the plan's finished!
But the Owl said they can't influence the
decision unless Zeke has decent scores.
I know! A chance like
this comes once a century!
Doesn't Zeke still have a shot, though?
Yeah, he might. If Zeke steps up--
--I'm sorry.
--Zeke!
I know you can do it!
You're our son, after all!
I said Marley has no need for you.
Why are you here?
T-To show my loyalty to Marley
and atone for Eldia's sins!
Let me in open training, please!
What are you doing, Jaeger?!
Run! Run, boy!
Dammit! It's bullshit!
Don't say that! He's trying his best!
He'll never be a Warrior like this!
You were a mess the other day.
It's not funny. They're just having me
run errands now. It's over for me.
Seemed to me that you never
wanted to be a Warrior.
I have to become one, yet I totally failed.
No big deal. It's stupid
for you to be a Warrior.
It's dumb to shorten your life for Marley
and get sent to fight other nations.
Huh?!
Why did you become a Warrior?
To learn the secrets of Titans.
I'm a researcher, you know.
Everything started when the
Founder Ymir touched "something,"
but I wanted to know the truth of it all--
enough to shorten my life
to look through Titan memories.
That's why I'm pretty much
useless when it comes to war.
Compared to the mysteries of Titans,
hatred and war seem so trivial.
That's why you and I aren't
interested in their war games.
We're just two decent people--
a real rarity in this world.
This is for the best. Even if I can't
leave the zone, as long as I'm alive...
We finally got a lead.
They're the "Eldian Restorationists."
It's a pretty large group.
A traitor called the "Owl" formed it.
We've got a few hunches already.
It's just a matter of time
till we get solid proof.
Zeke?
What's wrong?
Eat up.
M-My stomach hurts.
Dad, Mom... Stop doing dangerous things.
If they find out, we'll be sent to paradise--
sent to the island of devils
and made into Titans.
Have you learned nothing I've taught you?
Unless someone takes a stand,
we'll live pitiful lives in this tiny cage.
That's right. We're fighting for the
future of all Eldians, including yours.
Even if there's a chance
that I end up like Aunt Fay?
Zeke! The only reason Fay died
is because this world is twisted!
We have to fight so nobody
else ends up like her!
We must restore the strength of Eldia
and win our rights back!
"Information Available for Public Disclosure"
"Titan Research"
"Research concerning the unique power of Subjects of Ymir to become Titans. A field of study since the era of the Eldian
Empire, it encompasses not only the biology
of Titans themselves, but also the ideologies of Eldians who possess the power and how to deal with them. Though researched extensively over many years, the truth of Titans still remains a mystery."
You're kidding me!
Your parents are Restorationists?!
You'll all be sent to paradise!
Yeah.
Mr. Ksaver, thanks for playing catch with me.
Even when I'm a Titan, I'll remember you.
Well, goodbye.
Report them.
Huh?
It's your only hope!
If you report them to Marley
and prove your loyalty,
you and your grandparents might be spared.
I could never do that!
Zeke! Your parents have been terrible to you!
They gave up on you
and never cared how you felt!
They... never loved you!
Zeke, you've done nothing wrong.
You're a smart kid. A good kid.
Take it easy on me, Zeke!
Whoops. Do I throw too hard for a geezer?
Hey! I'm not that old--!
Mr. Ksaver!
It won't be long till my term is over.
Yeah.
I didn't get to grow old,
but I don't regret a life of research.
I'll be able to release a compilation.
Yeah? What about?
The things the Founding Titan
did to the Subjects of Ymir.
Oh. Like rewriting their memories?
Not just memories. It can change
the anatomy of their bodies.
Around 600 years ago, a terrible
pandemic devastated the population.
But all of a sudden, the disease just
vanished from the Eldian Empire.
The King at the time used the Founding
Titan to change how their bodies work.
No matter where we go, we Subjects of
Ymir are like part of the Founding Titan.
Scary, right?
Then...
Why are you pumping out more devils?!
Can the Founding Titan make it
so Subjects of Ymir can't bear children?
If none of us were able to have kids,
Titans would be wiped out in 100 years.
The world wouldn't have to fear
or be threatened by Titans anymore.
What's more, if we hadn't been born,
we wouldn't have had to suffer!
Mr. Ksaver?
I've never spoken about it,
but I had a family once.
In my foolish youth, I removed my armband.
And hiding the fact I was an Eldian,
I had a wife and child.
My wife was a Marleyan.
I knew I couldn't hide it forever,
but when my wife found out I was Eldian,
she slit my son's throat and her own.
Me becoming a Warrior was merely
a grandiose way to commit suicide, but...
For 13 years, I immersed myself in
Titan research, met you, played catch...
It's been fun.
I looked for my dead son in you.
I ran from my sins with my Titan powers!
If only I hadn't been born in this world!
I'll inherit the Beast Titan.
Not for Marley, but to retake the
Founding Titan and save the world!
I'll free the world from the terror of Titans
and free all Eldians from suffering!
This is something I haven't told Marley--
a way to break the vow renouncing war.
As luck would have it, it's only
possible because it's you.
If a Titan with royal blood comes
in contact with the Founding Titan,
it's possible to draw out its power.
However, the power isn't yours to use.
That right lies with the Founding Titan.
Essentially, you're the key to the lock.
The Founding Titan needs
to be someone you trust.
Someone who understands
our "euthanization" plan.
I know you'll find that someone.
I'll always be watching over you, Zeke.
I'll find that someone, Father.
Eren Jaeger?
Yes. Eren possesses the Founding Titan.
And in the basement of his house in Shiganshina
there's some sort of vital information.
Did you hear Eren say
anything about his father?
I believe he said his father's
missing and used to be a doctor.
Unbelievable! "That" father was alive?
Eren, we're victims.
You've been brainwashed by him.
Someday, I'll come and rescue you!
You're starting to resemble Father a bit.
First of all, thanks for coming
here to talk with me.
My stance is exactly what Yelena told you.
Do you support the Eldian euthanization plan?
Four years ago, some of Dad's
memories opened up to me--
memories of when he slaughtered
the wall's royal family.
He crushed their little kids
and smeared them like bugs.
I felt it, too.
If those kids lived, the royal family
would retake the Founding Titan.
Bound by the vow renouncing war,
humanity in the walls would be doomed.
Those kids dying is what let us live.
I see. So you believe that Father was right?
No, he was wrong.
And I, the son that he raised, was wrong, too.
If Eldians hadn't been born, this city--
these people wouldn't have
to die in this plan of ours.
There's no greater salvation
than never being born in this world.
I'll do it. I'll put an end
to 2,000 years of Titan domination.
Until then, I keep moving forward.
Right, Brother?
Yeah. Yeah, you're right. Let's do it.
I wish I could shake your hand, but it's best
that we don't make contact just yet.
So instead, take this.
Eren, we're gonna save everyone.
Our sole salvation...
...is Eldia's euthanization.
You say something? Euthanization?
You're about to find yourself
in a Titan's mouth,
listening to what it sounds like to be digested.
Compared to how you stole
the lives of my comrades,
it sounds like a pleasant way to die.
I didn't steal... I saved lives.
The lives of the children they would bear...
...from this cruel world.
--Looks like your legs are growing back.
--Isn't that right...
...Mr. Ksaver?! I hope you're watching!
The futures they seek are incompatible.
All they can do is clash,
fighting for their beliefs
in the place it all began, Shiganshina.
Next episode: "Above and Below."
"Above and Below"