Hey!
You're not allowed to touch the girl, mister.
I-It's not what you think, Hitch! I-I...
Titan memories have been known
to transfer by touch!
I thought I might learn something important!
I wasn't doing anything inappropriate, really!
You are a guy, after all.
I bet you wanna learn all about Annie.
I'm sorry, okay?!
Don't ban me from coming back!
I wasn't planning to. Annie would
get bored listening only to me.
Huh?
Unbelievable. You're so popular,
and all you do is sleep.
"Guides"
It's great that you've got a crush on her,
but have you heard the news?
No.
Read this.
"Military Clings to Power by
Wrongfully Detaining Eren Jaeger."
"Distrust in the Military Soars Higher."
Because they're not giving
the public any answers.
Well, they can't just disclose
Zeke and the rumbling.
Only Eren can save Eldia!
Jaeger's the only one who avenges the eaten!
The New Eldian Empire needs Eren Jaeger!
This is...
There're citizens surrounding the entire HQ.
Hey, Hitch! Lend us a hand!
Ugh! More work for me!
Armin!
Mikasa! You managed to make it here, huh?
Yeah. We can't let this time
go to waste. Let's go.
Scout recruits? What are they doing at HQ?
That day, I did go to meet Eren.
Oh?
I'm sorry for keeping quiet about it.
That's enough reason to detain the volunteers.
How kind of you to admit.
The way I saw it, you guys
didn't know the world.
If you kept arguing and putting it off,
it would be too late.
Eren felt the same sense of urgency, too.
So, you convinced Eren to infiltrate
Marley alone to get our military moving?
Not quite. I said someone needed to
light a fire under the administration.
That's all you said?
You risked a secret meeting without
discussing any concrete plans?
That's right.
Given our position, we weren't allowed
to meet with him in public.
But the risk was worth it to you.
You succeeded in manipulating Eren
just as Zeke hoped you would.
What would be the point in that?
All I wanted was for Eren Jaeger
to know who I was!
No... We wanted Eren's Founding Titan
to crush Marley into dust.
Just like we hoped,
he inflicted heavy damage to Marley.
No... He exceeded expectations.
He delivered the divine retribution
we wished upon Marley for years.
For him to achieve such things
is proof he possesses the Founder.
Commander Pyxis, do you know
what we're witnessing?
History is about to change before our eyes.
Two brothers are reshaping the world.
I simply want to see it happen from their side.
In other words, the main reason
you met Eren was out of curiosity?
Essentially. The other volunteers
don't know that I secretly met Eren.
My actions were reckless.
It's true that I deceived you guys,
but I did it for the sake of Eldia.
I'd like to believe you.
Tell me everything you and Eren spoke about.
Do you know how to tell a good lie?
Sometimes, you've gotta mix the truth into it.
Good grief. It's appalling that people
doubt us after all this time.
Aren't we comrades? We sweat
side-by-side these past three years!
The railways, the trading...
We made this island prosper!
We gave our everything to Eldia!
I'm sorry. It's just ten months after
the rails opened and this happens...
Tell me about it. Didn't we swear
to work together for the future?
Wh-What's the matter?!
What? Yelena said she
met Eren in secret? Seriously?
You really didn't know?
I-I had no idea. Honestly.
Yeah. It doesn't seem like
you did. To me, at least.
Yelena...
I notice you're not saying
Yelena would never do that.
Because you know that she might.
That's not...
We've done this backwards, but now
there's reason to detain you guys.
Tell me what you know about Yelena
for the sake of our future.
As you know, Yelena organized the volunteers.
At first, people were wary
and it didn't go so well.
But she got her hands dirty and proved
her loyalty to Zeke and the group.
There were "accidental" deaths.
We buried friends we ate and slept with.
Anyone who doubted us.
But we pushed on for the sake of our
homelands that Marley took away.
Strange.
Huh?
She pressed our government
to give Marleyans certain rights.
You make Yelena sound merciless
to Marleyans, yet on our island...
All right. I need you to
come with me, Onyankopon.
Huh?
I hear Hange's all over the place.
Yeah. I guess something needed checking out.
Indeed. And I permitted
a volunteer to go along.
I can't allow you two to meet Eren.
Why not?!
Because we know Eren had
contact with the volunteers.
Eren kept quiet about his secret meeting
which resulted in the raid on Marley.
We're currently investigating if
anyone else was involved with it.
Eren hasn't said a word
since the truth came to light.
We're still in the dark about what he did
during his time in Marley, too.
We believe that Eren is
being manipulated by Zeke.
I'm telling you this because it's you two,
but keep quiet about it.
Eren... No way...
What will happen to Eren?!
Is that...?
Hmm? It's nothing. I had recruits bring it here
since there was nowhere to store it.
But, Premier, if Eren isn't talking,
all the more reason I think we can help.
I'm not sure we can get the truth out
of him, but there's no harm in trying.
The situation is too delicate.
We're done talking here.
Why? You're right that there's no harm
in talking, so why can't we?
One explanation might be that
they've completely given up on Eren.
Excuse us!
If that's true, they're already
picking the next Founding Titan.
I'll listen through the door.
Wait, Mikasa!
It's fine. I won't get caught.
We can't risk it right now!
With all that's going on,
we've gotta find out their plan!
No matter what happens,
I'll make sure Eren...
Armin! You okay?
I-I'm fine.
--Put out the fire!
--Was anyone injured?!
--Over here! We need a hand!
--Hurry up!
You guys okay?!
Hitch! What was that?!
The premier's room just...!
Where is he?!
Give your hearts!
Our anger reached 'em! Now's the time to fight!
I'll fight, too!
--Me, too!
--And me!
--Yeah! It's time to fight!
--Let's show 'em how angry we are!
Give your hearts!
Give your hearts! Give your hearts!
Premier Zachary owned a "special" chair.
We believe a bomb was placed on it.
He and three soldiers were lost.
The culprit and their goal is unknown.
The volunteers were on house arrest
and this one was with me all day.
Who else could be responsible for it?
The premier said some recruits
brought it to his room.
Recruits from where?
He never said from where.
But when Mikasa and I went to his room,
we saw recruits leaving HQ.
Scout recruits.
Speaking of Scouts, I hear some
of them leaked the info about Eren.
--You don't think...
--It's an emergency!
Eren Jaeger has escaped from his cell!
Mobilize everyone and find him!
--Yes, sir!
--Hurry! Let's go!
--Armin...
What in the world is happening?
What a crowd. This everyone?
Besides us here, we have allies
hiding in the military.
Including some who blew up Dhalis Zachary.
The only one who can save the
Eldian Empire is you, Eren Jaeger.
It's okay, Mikasa. Eren will understand.
If we talk to him, I'm sure he'll understand.
Find out where Zeke's being kept.
"Information Available for Public Disclosure"
"New Eldian Empire"
"A new name for Eldia used by those on Paradis who are sympathetic to Eren Jaeger's actions. They have rallied around Eren and the name, causing disorder on the island, which is currently divided on whether to attack other nations or not."
Floch Forster and some 100 soldiers
and guards vanished from the prison.
They're thought to have defected
timed with Eren's escape.
I'm sure they're behind
the premier's murder, too.
They need a name. Let's call these
anti-military insurgents "Jaegerists."
And the goal of the Jaegerists...
is what, Hange?
They're hoping to bring Zeke and Eren together.
They'll reform the military with Eren on top.
Murdering the premier shows their resolve.
It's obvious what provoked them.
The military schemed to take the Founder
from Eren, all without telling us.
We knew what would happen if we had.
In any case, many of the
Jaegerists are from the Scouts.
How will you take responsibility, Hange?
I'll accept any punishment.
But resigning now would be
an irresponsible thing to do.
Besides, we don't know how many
Jaegerists are still in hiding.
Indeed. There might even be a
suicide bomber standing in front of me.
Roeg, don't be ridiculous.
Can you be trusted? Until we know,
we can't let you Scouts roam as you please!
Enough! We have a guest here!
We have more important things
to do than bicker!
Hange, who knows where Zeke's being held?
Levi and the 30 soldiers with him.
Also, three soldiers who deliver supplies.
Lastly, there's me.
Have those three brought here.
Nile, is the Queen's residence safe?
Only a few know the location,
but I'll check it out.
Eren will attempt to contact
Zeke and Queen Historia.
Protecting those two is an absolute must!
Yes, sir!
Commander Pyxis!
Now that we've lost the premier,
the only one who can lead us is you.
What do you think we should do?
We've been utterly beaten.
Let's surrender to Eren.
We can't do a thing about enemies in our midst.
Even if we flushed them out,
who knows how much blood it would cost?
We don't have time to waste on such folly.
Our decisions made soldiers
turn their backs on us.
It brought about our defeat.
You're kidding! Bow down to
the people who killed the premier?!
I knew Zachary for many years.
To live and die by revolution
would be what he wanted.
Anyways, the four who died wouldn't
want their deaths to cause Eldia's fall.
So instead, we submit to the Jaeger brothers?!
We're not submitting.
We'll use the location of Zeke
to negotiate with the Jaegerists.
Like before, Eldia's survival will depend
on a test run of the rumbling.
However, we must look past the fact
that they murdered the premier.
If that's the price to prevent
countless comrades from being killed...
...so be it.
Get moving, soldiers!
Yes, sir!
Commander.
I'm ashamed you had to see that.
Don't be. Every country goes through this.
I'm afraid I can't guarantee your safety.
Please wait at the port until all this is over.
Right. We're hoping for Eldia's victory
from the bottom of our hearts.
Lady Mikasa.
If anything happens, please escape to my ship.
I appreciate your concern, Lady Kiyomi.
However, I am an Eldian.
I want the place I was born to have a future.
Don't concern yourself with me.
What are you talking about?
The whole reason we came was for you!
Not our resources?
You don't care who leads the country
as long as the rumbling succeeds, right?
Yes... Unless the rumbling's power is proven,
Hizuru will hang us out to dry.
Our investments will go to waste
and the Azumabitos will be done for.
All the more reason I can't rely on you.
The Azumabitos had to adapt
to these turbulent times.
Now, we're best known for being
wretched, money-grubbing vixens.
Still, we haven't lost our pride in the clan
that your mother passed on to you.
No matter what comes of the country,
we wish to protect you!
We're helping Eren when he killed the premier?
Nobody knows if Eren did it.
Keep it down, Mikasa.
People suspect us of being Jaegerists.
Whose side are you on anyways, Mikasa?
Armin and I almost got caught
in the explosion. You have to ask?
--Huh?
--Enough.
Like Pyxis was saying,
infighting will be our downfall.
So you're okay with entrusting
everything to Eren and Zeke?
No, it's not good.
Zeke and Yelena took precautions and
were ready for this sort of situation.
We have to expect they took
other precautions, too.
We need to figure out Zeke's intentions
before he makes fools of us.
Let's just hope my concerns
turn out to be nothing.
Something worrying you?
Yelena secured work for
Marleyan prisoners in odd places.
Like restaurants, for example.
What a big building!
I've never seen anything like it!
Me, either!
It's yer lucky day, kids!
Y'all fixin' to eat?
Yeah!
Tsk! The military's always in a rush.
Gabi and Falco seek help
from a Marleyan prisoner.
Does a rewarding future lie beyond
the truth, or something else?
Next episode: "Children of the Forest."
"Children of the Forest"